Subtitles by demonseye
I was sitting with my friend
Arthur Kornblum in a restaurant.
It was a Horn & Hardart cafeteria.
And this beautiful girl walked in,
and I turned to Arthur
and I said "Arthur, you see that girl?
I'm going to marry her."
And two weeks later
we were married.
And it's over 50 years later,
and we're still married.
- I love you.
Oh, hi, Sally.
Sally, this is Harry Burns.
- Harry, this is Sally Albright.
- Nice to meet you.
- Wanna drive the first shift?
- No, you're there already. You can start.
Back's open.
- Call me.
- I'll call you as soon as I get there.
- Call me from the road.
- I'll call you before that.
- I love you.
Sorry.
- I miss you already.
- I miss you.
- I miss you already. Bye.
- Bye.
I have it all figured out.
It's an 18-hour trip,
which breaks down into
six shifts of three hours each,
or, alternatively,
we could break it down by mileage.
There's a...
There's a map on the visor
that I've... marked to show
the locations where we can change shifts.
Grape?
No. I don't like to eat
between meals.
I'll roll down the window.
Why don't you tell me
the story of your life?
The story of my life?
We got 18 hours to kill
before we hit New York.
The story of my life doesn't
even get us out of Chicago.
I mean, nothing's
happened to me yet.
- That's why I'm going to New York.
- So something'll happen to you?
- Yes.
- Like what?
Like I'm going to journalism school
to become a reporter.
So you can write about things
that happen to other people.
- That's one way to look at it.
- Suppose nothing happens to you.
Suppose you live there your whole life
and nothing happens,
you never meet anybody,
you never become anything,
then you finally die
one of those New York deaths
when nobody notices for two weeks
until the smell drifts into the hallway.
- Amanda mentioned you had a dark side.
- That's what drew her to me.
- Your dark side?
- Sure. Why, don't you have a dark side?
I know, you're probably
one of those cheerful people
who dots your "i"s
with little hearts.
I have just as much of
a dark side as the next person.
Oh, really? When I buy a new book,
I always read the last page first.
That way, in case I die before I finish,
I know how it ends.
That, my friend,
is a dark side.
That doesn't mean
you're deep or anything.
I mean... yes, basically
I'm a happy person.
So am I.
And I don't see that
there's anything wrong with that.
Of course not, you're
too busy being happy.
Do you ever think
about death?
- Yes.
- Sure you do. A fleeting thought
that you're just sending out
of the transom of your mind.
I spend hours, I spend days.
And you think
this makes you a better person.
Look, when the shit comes down,
I'm gonna be prepared and you're not.
That's all I'm sayin'.
In the meantime, you're gonna
ruin your whole life waiting for it.
- You're wrong.
- I'm not wrong.
- He wants her to leave.
- That's why he puts her on the plane.
- I don't think she wants to stay.
Of course she wants to stay.
Wouldn't you rather be with
Humphrey Bogart than the other guy?
I don't wanna spend
the rest of my life in Casablanca
married to a man
who runs a bar.
That probably sounds
very snobbish to you, but I don't.
- You'd rather be in a passionless marriage...
- And be the First Lady of Czechoslovakia.
And live with a man man you had
the greatest sex of your life with,
just because he owns a bar
and that is all he does?
Yes.
And so would any woman in
her right mind. Women are practical,
even Ingrid Bergman, which is why she
gets on the plane at the end of the movie.
I understand.
- What? What?
- Nothing.
- What?
- Forget about it.
- Forget about what? Forget about what?
- It's not important.
No, just tell me.
Obviously, you haven't had
great sex yet.
- Two, please.
- Right over there.
- Yes, I have.
- No, you haven't.
It just so happens that
I have had plenty of good sex.
With whom?
- What?
- With whom did you have this great sex?
I'm not gonna tell you that.
Fine. Don't tell me.
- Shel Gordon.
- Shel. Sheldon?
No. No, you did not have
great sex with... Sheldon.
- I did, too.
- No, you didn't.
A Sheldon can do
your income taxes.
If you need a root canal,
Sheldon's your man.
But humpin' and pumpin' is not
Sheldon's strong suit. It's the name.
"Do it to me, Sheldon."
"You're an animal... Sheldon."
"Ride me, big... Sheldon."
- It doesn't work.
- Hi.
- What can I get you?
- I'll have a number three.
I'd like the chef's salad, please, with
the oil and vinegar on the side.
And the apple pie a la mode.
Chef and apple a la mode.
But I'd like the pie heated
and I don't want the ice cream on top,
I want it on the side.
And I'd like strawberry
instead of vanilla, if you have it.
If not, then no ice cream,
just whipped cream, but only if it's real.
If it's out of a can, then nothing.
- Not even the pie?
- No, just the pie, but then not heated.
Uh-huh.
- What?
- Nothin'. Nothin'.
So, how come
you broke up with Sheldon?
How do you know
we broke up?
Because, if you didn't break up,
you wouldn't be here with me.
You'd be off with Sheldon
the Wonder Schlong.
First of all,
I am not with you.
And second of all, it is none
of your business why we broke up.
You're right, you're right.
I don't wanna know.
Well, if you must know,
it was because he was very jealous
and I had these
days-of-the-week underpants.
I'm sorry, I need
a judge's ruling on this.
- Days-of-the-week underpants?
- Yes.
They had days of the week on them
and I thought they were sort of funny.
And then one day Sheldon says to me
"You never wear Sunday."
He's all suspicious. Where was Sunday?
Where had I left Sunday?
And I told him
and he didn't believe me.
- What?
- They don't make Sunday.
- Why not?
- Because of God.
Okay, so 15%
of my share is... 90.
6.90.
Let's leave seven.
What?
Do I have
something on my face?
You're a very attractive person.
Thank you.
Amanda never said
how attractive you were.
Well, maybe she doesn't think
I'm attractive.
I don't think it's a matter of opinion.
Empirically, you are attractive.
Amanda is my friend.
So?
- So you're going with her.
- So?
So you're coming on to me.
No, I wasn't.
What?
Can't a man say a woman is attractive
without it being a come-on?
All right, all right.
Let's just say, just for the sake
of argument, that it was a come-on.
What d'you want me to do about it?
I take it back, okay? I take it back.
You can't take it back.
- Why not?
- Because it's already out there.
Oh, geez, what are we supposed to do?
Call the cops, it's already out there.
Just let it lie.
- Okay?
- Great. "Let it lie." That's my policy.
That's what
I always say. "Let it lie."
Wanna spend the night
in a motel?
- See what I did? I didn't let it lie.
- Harry.
I said I would,
and I didn't.
- Harry!
- I walked the other way.
- Harry.
- What?
We are just
going to be friends, okay?
Great. Friends.
It's the best thing.
You realize of course
that we could never be friends.
- Why not?
- What I'm saying is,
and this is not a come-on
in any way, shape or form,
is that men and women
can't be friends,
because the sex part
always gets in the way.
That's not true. I have
a number of men friends
and there is
no sex involved.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
You only think you do.
You're saying I'm having sex
with these men without my knowledge?
No, what I'm saying is
they all wanna have sex with you.
- They do not.
- Do, too.
How do you know?
Because no man can be friends
with a woman that he finds attractive.
He always wants
to have sex with her.
So, you're saying that a man can be friends
with a woman he finds unattractive.
No, you pretty much
wanna nail them, too.
What if they don't
wanna have sex with you?
Doesn't matter. Because the sex thing
is already out there,
so the friendship is ultimately doomed
and that is the end of the story.
Well, I guess we're not
gonna be friends then.
- Guess not.
- That's too bad.
You were the only person
that I knew in New York.
- Thanks for the ride.
- Yeah. It was interesting.
- It was nice knowing you.
- Yeah.
- Well, have a nice life.
- You, too.
- We fell in love in high school.
- Yeah, we were high-school sweethearts.
But then after our junior year
his parents moved away.
- But I never forgot her.
- He never forgot me.
No, her face
was burned on my brain.
And it was 34 years later
that I was walking down Broadway
and I saw her
come out of Toffenetti's.
We both looked
at each other,
and it was just as though
not a single day had gone by.
She was just as beautiful
as she was at sixteen.
He was just the same.
He looked
exactly the same.
Joe. I thought it was you.
I thought it was you.
- Harry Burns.
- Harry, Harry. How ya doin'?
- Good. How you doin'?
- Uh, fine. I'm doin' fine.
That's great. I was just walking by
and I thought it was you.
- And there it is, it was you.
- Yeah, yeah, it was.
You still with the DA's office?
No, I switched to the other side.
W-what about you?
I work with a small firm.
We do political consulting. Yeah, it's great.
Oh, Harry, this is Sally Albright.
Harry Burns. Uh...
Harry and I, we used to, uh...
We lived in the same building.
Well, listen, I got a plane to catch.
It was really good to see you, Joe.
- You too, Harry.
- Bye.
Thank God
he couldn't place me.
I drove from college to New York
with him five years ago
and it was
the longest night of my life.
- What happened?
- He made a pass at me. And when I said no,
he was going
with a girlfriend of mine, uh...
Oh, God,
I can't remember her name.
Don't get involved
with me, Joe.
I am 26 years old and I can't
even remember the name of the girl
I was such good friends with
I wouldn't get involved
with her boyfriend.
- So what happened?
- When?
When-when he made
a pass at you, you said no...
Oh, oh. I said
we could just be friends.
And this part I remember.
He said that men and women
could never really be friends.
Do you think that's true?
No.
Do you have any women friends,
just friends?
No.
But I will get one
if it's important to you.
Amanda Reese.
That was her name. Thank God.
I will miss you.
I love you.
- You do?
- Yes.
I love you.
- And what would you like to drink?
- Nothing, thanks.
- D'you have any Bloody Mary mix?
- Yes.
No, wait. Here's what I want.
Regular tomato juice,
fill it up
about three quarters,
then add a splash of
Bloody Mary mix - just a splash -
and a little piece of lime
on the side.
The University of Chicago,
right?
Yes.
Did you look this good
at the University of Chicago?
- No.
- Did we ever...?
No. No.
We drove from Chicago to New York
together after graduation.
- Would you two like to sit together?
- Great! Thank you.
You were a good friend of, um...
Amanda's. I can't believe
you can't remember her name.
What do you mean? I can remember.
Amanda, right? Amanda Rice.
Reese.
Reese, right. That's what I said.
Whatever happened to her?
- I have no idea.
- You have no idea?
You were really
good friends with her.
We didn't make it
because you were such good friends.
- You went with her.
- And was it worth it?
The sacrifice for a friend that
you don't even keep in touch with?
Harry, you might
not believe this,
but I never considered
not sleeping with you a sacrifice.
Fair enough. Fair enough.
- You were gonna be a gymnast.
- A journalist.
- Right, that's what I said. And?
- I am a journalist. I work at The News.
Great. And you're with Joe.
Well, that's great. Great.
You're together, what,
three weeks?
- A month. How did you know that?
- You take someone to the airport,
it's clearly the beginning
of a relationship.
That's why I have never
taken anyone to the airport
at the beginning
of a relationship.
- Why?
- Because eventually things move on
and you don't take
someone to the airport.
And I never wanted anyone
to say to me:
"How come you never take me
to the airport any more?"
It's amazing.
You look like a normal person,
but actually you are
the Angel of Death.
Are you gonna marry him?
We have only known
each other for a month
and, besides, neither one of us
is looking into getting married right now.
- I'm getting married.
- You are?
- Yeah.
Who is she?
Helen Hillson. She's a lawyer.
She's keeping her name.
- You're getting married.
- Yeah.
What's so funny about that?
It, uh... It's just
so optimistic of you, Harry.
Well, you'd be amazed what
falling madly in love can do for you.
Well, it's wonderful. It's nice
to see you embracing life in this manner.
Yeah. Plus, you know,
you just get to a certain point
where you get tired
of the whole thing.
- What whole thing?
- The whole "life of a single guy" thing.
You meet someone,
you have the safe lunch,
you decide to like each other or not
to move on to dinner.
You go dancing,
you do the white man's overbite,
you go back to her place,
you have sex,
and the minute you're finished
you know what goes through your mind?
"How long do I have
to lie here and hold her
before I can get up
and go home?"
"Is 30 seconds enough?"
That's what you're thinking?
Is that true?
Sure. All men think that.
How long do you like to be
held afterwards? All night, right?
See, that's the problem.
Somewhere between 30 seconds
and all night is your problem.
- I don't have a problem.
- Yeah, you do.
- Staying over?
- Yes.
Would you like to have dinner?
Just friends.
I thought you didn't believe
men and women could be friends.
- When did I say that?
- On the ride to New York.
No, no, no, no,
I never said that.
Yes, that's right.
They can't be friends.
Unless both of them are involved
with other people.
Then they can. This is
an amendment to the earlier rule.
If two people are in relationships, the
pressure of possible involvement is lifted.
That doesn't work either
because what happens then
is the person you're involved with
can't understand
why you need to be friends with
the person you're just friends with,
like it means something
is missing from the relationship
and you want to go outside
to get it.
Then when you say "No, no, no, no,
it's not true,
nothing is missing
from our relationship",
the person you're involved with and
accuses you of being secretly attracted
to the person you're just friends with,
which you probably are.
I mean, come on, who the hell
are we kidding? Let's face it.
Which brings us back to the earlier rule
before the amendment, which is
men and women can't be friends.
So where's that leave us?
- Harry.
- What?
- Goodbye.
- Okay.
I'll just stop walking.
I'll let you go ahead.
We were married
40 years ago.
We were married three years,
we got a divorce. Then I married Marjorie.
- But first you lived with Barbara.
- Right, Barbara.
But I didn't marry Barbara.
I married Marjorie.
- Then you got a divorce.
- Right. Then I married Katie.
Another divorce.
Then a couple of years later at
Eddie Collecio's funeral, I ran into her.
I was with some girl
I don't even remember.
- Roberta.
- Right. Roberta.
But I couldn't
take my eyes off you.
I remember I snuck over
to her and I said...
- What did I say?
- You said "What are you doin' after?"
Right. So I ditch Roberta, we go
for coffee, a month later we're married.
35 years today
after our first marriage.
I went through his pockets,
okay?
Marie, why did you go
through his pockets?
- You know what I found?
- No, what?
They just bought
a dining-room table.
I mean, his wife just went out and spent
1,600 dollars on a dining-room table.
- Where?
- The point isn't where, Alice.
The point is he's never
gonna leave her.
So, what else is new?
You've known this for two years.
You're right. You're right,
I know you're right.
Why can't you find
someone single?
When I was single,
I knew lots of nice single men.
There must be someone.
Sally found someone.
Well, Sally got
the last good one.
- Joe and I broke up.
- What?
- When?
- Monday.
- You waited three days to tell us?
- Joe's available?
For God's sake, Marie,
don't you have any feelings about this?
- She's obviously upset.
- I'm not that upset.
We'd been growing apart
for quite a while.
But you guys were a couple.
You had someone to go places with.
You had a date on national holidays.
I said to myself
"You deserve more than this.
You're 31 years old..."
And the clock is ticking.
No, the clock doesn't really start
to tick until you're 36.
God, you're
in such great shape.
Well, I've had a few days
to get used to it, and, uh... I feel okay.
Good.
Then you're ready.
- Really, Marie.
- Well, how else do you think you do it?
I've got the perfect guy.
I don't happen to find him
attractive, but you might.
She doesn't have
a problem with chins.
- Marie, I'm not ready yet.
- But you just said you were over him.
I am over him,
but I'm in a mourning period.
- Who is it?
- Alex Anderson.
You fixed me up with him
six years ago.
Sorry. God.
All right, wait.
Here. Here we go.
- Ken Darman.
- He's been married for over a year.
Really?
Married.
- Oh, wait. Wait, Wait.
- Look...
I got one.
There is no point in my going out
with someone I might really like
if I met him at the right time,
but who right now has no chance
of being anything to me
but a transitional man.
Okay, but don't wait too long. Remember
what happened with David Warsaw?
His wife left him
and everyone said
"Give him some time.
Don't move in too fast."
Six months later
he was dead.
What are you saying, I should
get married to someone right away
in case he's about to die?
At least you could say
you were married.
I'm saying that the right man,
he might be out there right now.
And if you don't grab him,
someone else will,
and you'll have to spend
the rest of your life
knowing that someone else
is married to your husband.
Ten. Hut!
- When did this happen?
- Friday. Helen comes home from work
and she says "I don't know
if I wanna be married any more."
Like it's the institution.
You know, like it's nothing personal,
just something she's been
thinking about in a casual way.
I'm calm. I say "Why don't we take
some time to think about it?
You know,
don't rush into anything."
- Yeah, right.
- Next day she says she's thought about it.
And she wants a trial separation.
She just wants to try it, she says.
But we can still date.
Like this is supposed to cushion the blow.
Man, I got married
so I could stop dating,
so I don't see why we can still date
is any big incentive
since the last thing you wanna do
is date your wife,
who's supposed to love you.
Which is what
I'm saying to her,
when it occurs to me
that maybe she doesn't.
So I say to her
"Don't you love me any more?"
D'you know what she says?
"I don't know if I've ever loved you."
Ooh, that's harsh. You don't
bounce back from that right away.
- Thanks, Jess.
- No, I'm a writer. I know dialogue.
And that's particularly harsh.
Then she tells me that somebody
in her office is going to South America
and she can sublet his apartment.
I can't believe this. And the doorbell rings.
"I can sublet his apartment"...
The words are still hanging in the air
you know, like in a balloon
attached to a mouth...
- Like a cartoon.
- Right.
So I go to the door and there are moving
men there. Now I start to get suspicious.
I say "Helen, when did you call
these movers?"
And she doesn't say anything.
So I ask the movers "When did
this woman book you for this gig?"
And they're just standing there.
Three huge guys, one of them
wearing a T-shirt that says
"Don't fuck with Mr Zero."
So I said "Helen, when did you make this
arrangement?" She says "A week ago."
I said "You've known for a week
and you didn't tell me?"
And she says
"I didn't wanna ruin your birthday."
You're saying Mr. Zero knew you were
getting a divorce a week before you did?
- Mr. Zero knew.
- I can't believe this.
I haven't told you
the bad part yet.
What could be worse
than Mr Zero knowing?
It's all a lie.
She's in love with somebody else.
Some tax attorney.
- She moved in with him.
- How did you find out?
I followed her.
Stood outside the building.
- That's so humiliating.
- Tell me about it.
And, you know, I knew.
I knew the whole time
that even though we were happy,
it was an illusion.
And that one day
she would kick the shit outta me.
Marriages don't break up
on account of infidelity.
It's just a symptom that
something else is wrong.
Oh, really? Well,
that symptom is fucking my wife.
So I just happened to see
his American Express bill.
What do you mean
"just happened" to see it?
Well, he was... shaving,
and... there it was in his briefcase.
What if he came out and
saw you look into his briefcase?
You're missing the point.
I'm telling you what I found.
He just spent 120 dollars
on a new nightgown for his wife.
I don't think
he's ever gonna leave her.
No one thinks
You're right, you're right.
I know you're right.
Someone is staring at you
in Personal Growth.
I know him.
You'd like him. He's married.
- Who is he?
- Harry Burns. He's a political consultant.
He's cute.
- You think he's cute?
- How do you know he's married?
Cause last time I saw him
he was getting married.
- When was that?
- Six years ago.
So he might not
be married any more.
Also, he's obnoxious.
This is just like in the movies,
remember, "The Lady Vanishes",
when she says to him
"You're the most obnoxious man"...
- "The most contemptible".
- ... then they fall madly in love.
- Also, he never remembers me.
- Sally Albright.
- Hi, Harry.
- I thought it was you.
It is. This is Marie.
Was Marie.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- How's Joe?
I hear he's fine.
- You're not with Joe any more?
- We just broke up.
I'm sorry. That's too bad.
Yeah. Well, you know.
Yeah.
So...
- What about you?
- I'm fine.
How's married life?
Not so good.
I'm getting a divorce.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah, well,
what're you gonna do?
What happened with you guys?
When Joe and I started seeing each other
we wanted exactly the same thing.
We wanted to live together
but we didn't wanna get married
because every time
anyone we knew got married,
it ruined their relationship.
They practically never had sex again.
It's true. That's one of the secrets
that no one ever tells you.
I would sit around with my girlfriends
who have kids and...
Actually, my-my one girlfriend
who has kids, Alice,
and she would complain about
how she and Gary never did it any more.
She didn't even complain about it,
now that I think about it.
She just said it matter-of-factly.
She said... they were up all night,
they were both exhausted all the time,
the kids just took every sexual impulse
they had out of them.
Joe and I used to talk about it
and we would say
"We're so lucky.
We have this wonderful relationship.
We can... have sex on the kitchen floor
and not worry about the kids walking in."
"We can fly off to Rome
on a moment's notice."
And then one day I was taking
Alice's girl for the afternoon
cause I promised to take her to the circus.
And... we were in the cab playing I-spy.
"I spy a mailbox",
"I spy a lamp post".
And she looked out the window
and she saw this man and this woman
with these two little kids, and the... man
had one of the kids on his shoulders.
And she said...
"I spy a family."
And I started to cry.
You know, I just started crying.
And I went home
and I said "The thing is, Joe,
we never do fly off to Rome
on a moment's notice."
And the kitchen floor...?
Not once. It's this very cold,
hard, Mexican ceramic tile.
Anyway,
we talked about it
for a long time.
And I said "This is what I want"
and he said "Well, I don't".
And I said "Well, I guess it's over."
And he left.
And the thing is,
I... I feel really fine.
I am over him.
I mean, I really am over him.
That was it for him.
That was the most that he could give.
And every time
I think about it,
I am more and more convinced
that I did the right thing.
Boy, you sound really healthy.
Yeah.
- At least I got the apartment.
- That's what everybody says to me too.
But really, what's so hard
about finding an apartment?
What you do is
you read the obituary column.
You find out who died,
go to the building,
and then you tip the doorman.
What they could do
to make it easier
is combine the obituaries
with the real-estate section.
Say, then you have "Mr Klein died,
say, leaving a wife, two children
and a spacious
three-bedroom apartment
with a wood- burning fireplace."
You know, the first time we met
I really didn't like you that much.
- I didn't like you.
- Yeah, you did.
You were just so uptight then.
You're much softer now.
You know, I hate
that kind of remark.
It sounds like a compliment,
but really it's an insult.
Okay, you're still
as hard as nails.
I just didn't wanna
sleep with you
and you had to write it off
as a character flaw,
instead of dealing
with the possibility
that it might have
something to do with you.
What's the statute of limitations
on apologies?
- Ten years.
- Ooh, I can just get it in under the wire.
Would you like to have
dinner with me sometime?
Are we becoming friends now?
Well...
Yeah.
Great. A woman friend.
You know, you may be
the first attractive woman
I've not wanted to sleep with
in my entire life.
That's wonderful, Harry.
We were both born
in the same hospital...
In 1921.
- .. seven days apart.
- In the same hospital.
- We both grew up one block apart.
- We both lived in tenements.
- On the Lower East Side.
- On Delancey Street.
- My family moved to the Bronx when I was ten.
- He lived on Fordham Road.
- Hers moved when she was 11.
- I lived on 183rd Street.
For 6 years, she worked
on the 15th floor...
I worked
for a prominent neurologist.
... as a nurse,
- where I had a practice on the 14th floor.
- Dr. Permelman.
The very same building.
- We never met.
- Never met.
- Can you imagine that?
- You know where we met? In an elevator.
- I was visiting family.
- In the Ambassador Hotel in Chicago.
He was on the third floor,
I was on the 12th.
I rode up nine extra floors
just to keep talking to her.
Nine extra floors.
- Hello.
- You sleeping?
- No, I was watching "Casablanca".
- Channel, please?
- Eleven.
- Thank you. Got it.
Now, you're telling me
you'd be happier with Victor Laszlo
than with Humphrey Bogart?
- When did I say that?
- When we drove to New York.
- I never said that. I would never say that.
- All right, fine. Have it your way.
- You been sleeping?
- Why?
Cause I haven't been sleeping.
I really miss Helen.
Maybe I'm coming down
with something.
Last night, I was up
at 4 in the morning
watching "Leave It to Beaver"
in Spanish.
"Buenos das, Seor Cleaver.
Dnde estn Wallace y Theodore?"
I'm not well.
Well, I went to bed at 7.30 last night.
I haven't done that since the third grade.
Well, that's the good thing
about depression. Get your rest.
- I'm not depressed.
- Okay, fine.
Do you still sleep
on the same side of the bed?
I did for a while, but now
I'm pretty much using the whole bed.
God, that's great. I feel weird
when just my leg wanders over.
I miss her.
- I don't miss him. I really don't.
- Not even a little?
You know what I miss?
I miss the idea of him.
Maybe I only miss
the idea of Helen.
No, I miss the whole Helen.
Last scene.
Goodbye, Rick.
God bless you.
Ooh, Ingrid Bergman.
Now, she's low maintenance.
- Low maintenance?
- There are two kinds of women.
High maintenance
and low maintenance.
And Ingrid Bergman
is low maintenance?
An LM, definitely.
- Which one am I?
- You're the worst kind.
You're high maintenance but
you think you're low maintenance.
- I don't see that.
- You don't see that?
"Waiter, I'll begin
with a house salad,
but I don't want
the regular dressing.
I'll have the balsamic vinegar
and oil, but on the side.
And then the salmon
with mustard sauce,
but I want the mustard sauce
on the side."
"On the side" is
a very big thing for you.
No, I just want it
the way I want it.
I know.
High maintenance.
Well, 10,000 francs
should pay our expenses.
Our expenses?
Louis, I think this is the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
Ooh, best last line
of a movie ever.
I'm definitely coming down
with something.
Probably a 24-hour tumour.
They're going around.
- You don't have a tumour.
- How do you know?
- If you're so worried, go see a doctor.
- No, he'll just tell me it's nothing.
- Will you be able to sleep?
- If not, I'll be okay.
- What'll you do?
- I'll stay up and moan.
Maybe I should practise now.
- Good night, Harry.
- Good night.
I had my dream again. Where I'm making
love and Olympic judges are watching?
I'd nailed the compulsories,
so this is it. The finals.
I got a 9.8 from the Canadian,
a perfect 10 from the American,
and my mother, disguised as
an East German judge, gave me a 5.6.
Must've been the dismount.
And basically it's the same one
I've been having since I was 12.
- What happens?
- No, it's... It's too embarrassing.
- Don't tell me.
- Okay, there's this guy.
- What's he look like?
- I don't know. He's just kinda faceless.
A faceless guy.
Okay. Then what?
He rips off my clothes.
- Then what happens?
- That's it.
That's it? A faceless guy
rips off your clothes
and that's the sex fantasy
you've been having
since you were 12.
Exactly the same.
Well, sometimes
I vary it a little.
- Which part?
- What I'm wearing.
- What?
- Nothing.
I have decided that
for the rest of the day
we are going to talk
like this.
- Like this?
- No. Please. To repeat after me.
- Pepper.
Waiter, there is too much pepper
on my paprikash.
Waiter, there is too much pepper...
But I would be proud
to partake of your pecan pie.
Oh, no.
- But I would be proud...
- ... to partake...
- ... of your pecan pie.
- Pecan pie.
Would you like to go
to the movies with me tonight?
Would you like to go...
what-what...
Not to repeat.
Please, to answer.
Would you like to go
to the movies with me... tonight?
Oh... Oh... Well, I'd love to, Harry,
but I-I can't.
What do you have?
A hot date?
- Well, yeah. Yeah.
- Really?
Yeah. I wa... was gonna tell you,
but, I don't know,
I just... I felt strange
about it.
Why?
Well, because we've been spending
so much time together.
Oh, I think it's great
that you have a date.
- You do?
- Yeah.
- Is that what you're gonna wear?
Well, I don't-don't know. Why?
I think you should wear skirts more.
You look really good in skirts.
- I do?
- Yeah.
You know, I have a theory
that hieroglyphics are really
an ancient comic strip about
a character named Sphinxy.
You know, Harry, I think
you should get out there, too.
Oh, I'm not ready.
You should.
I would not be good
for anybody right now.
It's time.
It was the most
uncomfortable night of my life.
See, no,
it has to go this way.
The first date back
is always the toughest, Harry.
You only had one date.
How do you know
it's not gonna get worse?
How much worse can it get
than finishing dinner,
having him reach over,
pull a hair out of my head and
start flossing with it at the table?
We're talking dream date
compared to my horror.
It started out fine.
She's a very nice person.
And we're sitting
and we're talking
in this Ethiopian restaurant
that she wanted to go to.
I was making jokes,
you know, like
"Hey, I didn't know that
they had food in Ethiopia."
"This'll be a quick meal. I'll order
two empty plates and we can leave."
Yeah. Nothing from her,
not even a smile.
So I downshift into small talk and
I ask here where she went to school.
And she says Michigan State.
This reminds me of Helen.
All of a sudden I'm in the middle
of this massive anxiety attack.
My heart's beatin' like a wild man
and I start sweatin' like a pig.
- Helen went to Michigan State?
- No, she went to Northwestern.
But they're both
Big Ten schools.
I got so upset
I had to leave the restaurant.
Harry, I think
this takes a long time.
It might be months
before we're actually able
to enjoy going out
with someone new.
Yeah.
And maybe longer,
before we're actually able
to go to bed
with someone new.
Oh, I went to bed with her.
- You went to bed with her?:
- Sure.
- I don't understand this relationship.
- What d'ya mean?
- You enjoy being with her?
- Yeah.
- You find her attractive?
- And you're not sleeping with her?
- No.
You're afraid
to let yourself be happy.
Why can't you gimme credit for this?
This is a big thing for me.
I never had a relationship
with a woman that didn't involve sex.
See, like I'm growing.
Are you finished?
Hey, I got a whole stack o' quarters.
And I was here first.
- Were not.
- Was too.
- Big jerk.
- Little creep.
- Where was I?
- You were growing.
Yeah.
It's very freeing.
I can say anything to her.
Are you saying you can say things
to her you can't say to me?
No, it's just different.
It's a whole different perspective.
I get the woman's
point of view on things.
She tells me about the men
that she goes out with,
- You tell her about other women?
- Yeah.
Like the other night. I made love
to this woman and it was so incredible...
I took her to a place that wasn't human.
She actually meowed.
You made a woman meow?
Yeah, that's the point.
I can say these things to her.
And the great thing is,
I don't have to lie
because I'm not always thinking
about how to get her into bed.
- I can just be myself.
- You made a woman meow?
What do you do with these women?
You just get up out of bed and leave?
Sure.
Oh, explain to me how you do it.
What do you say?
I say I have an early meeting,
early hair cut or a squash game.
- You don't play squash.
- They don't know that. They just met me.
- That's disgusting.
- I know. I feel terrible.
You know, I'm so glad
I never got involved with you.
I just would've ended up
being some woman
you had to get outta bed
and leave at 3 oclock in the morning
and go clean your andirons.
And you don't even have a fireplace.
Not that I would know this.
Why are you getting so upset?
This isn not about you.
Yes, it is. You are a human affront
to all women, and I am a woman.
Hey, I don't feel great about this
but I don't hear anyone complaining.
Of course not.
You're out the door too fast.
- I think they have an okay time.
- How do you know?
What d'you mean
how do I know? I know.
- Because they...
- Yes, because they...
How do you know
that they're really...
What are you saying?
That they fake orgasm?
- It's possible.
- Get outta here.
Why? Most women
at one time or another have faked it.
- Well, they haven't faked it with me.
- How do you know?
Because I know.
Oh... Right. That's right.
I forgot. You're a man.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Nothing.
It's just that all men are sure
it never happened to them
and most women at one time
or another have done it,
so you do the math.
You don't think that
I can tell the difference?
- No.
- Get outta here.
Are you okay?
Oh, God.
Ooh, oh, God.
Oh, yeah, right there.
Oh, God.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
Oh, yes: Yes: Yes:
Oh, God.
I'll have
what she's having.
He'll say "Are you married?"
I like you without your beard.
You see your face.
And it's my face.
- Whoa! Dipping you.
- Oh!
I really wanna thank you
for taking me out tonight.
Oh, don't be silly.
The next New Year's Eve, if neither
of us is with anybody, you got a date.
Deal.
See? Now we can dance
cheek to cheek.
That I love you a lot
Hey, everybody!
Ten seconds to New Year.
- Ten, nine...
- Wanna get some air?
- Yeah.
- ... seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one!
Happy New Year!
- Happy New Year.
He was a head counsellor
at the boys' camp,
and I was a head counsellor
at girls' camp,
and they had a social one night,
and he walked across the room.
I thought he was coming
to talk to my friend Maxine,
cause people were always
crossing rooms to talk to Maxine.
But he was coming to talk to me,
and he said
"I'm Ben Small
of the Coney Island Smalls."
At that moment I knew. I knew
the way you know about a good melon.
You sent flowers to yourself.
60 dollars I spent on this big stupid
arrangement of flowers, and I wrote a card
that I planned to leave
on the front table
where Arthur would just...
happen to see it.
What did the card say?
"Please say yes.
Love, Jonathan."
- Did it work?
- He never even came over.
He forgot this charity thing that his wife is
chairman of. He's never gonna leave her.
Of course he isn't.
You're right, you're right.
I know you're right.
- Where is this place?
- Somewhere on the next block.
Ohh! I can't believe
I'm doing this.
Look, Harry is one of my best friends
and you are one of my best friends.
And if by some chance
you two hit it off,
then we can all still be friends,
instead of... drifting apart
the way you do
when you get involved
with someone
who doesn't know your friends.
You and I haven't drifted apart
since I started seeing Arthur.
If Arthur ever left his wife
and I actually met him,
I am sure that you and I
would drift apart.
- He's never gonna leave her.
- Of course he isn't.
You're right, you're right.
I know you're right.
- I dunno about this.
- It's just a dinner.
You know, I've finally gotten
to a place in my life
where I'm comfortable with the fact
that it's just me and my work.
If she's so great,
why aren't you taking her out?
How many times do I have
to tell you? We're just friends.
So you're saying
she's not that attractive?
No, I told you,
she is attractive.
Yeah, but you also said
she had a good personality.
She has a good personality.
What?
When someone's not
that attractive,
they're always described
as having a good personality.
Look. If you would ask me
what does she look like
and I said "She has a good personality",
that means she's not attractive.
But just because I happened to mention
that she has a good personality,
she could be either.
She could be attractive
with a good personality,
or not attractive
with a good personality.
- So which one is she?
- Attractive.
But not beautiful, right?
It's like, whenever
I read Jimmy Breslin,
it's as if he's leaving
some kind of a... a wake-up call
- for the City of New York.
- What d'you mean by "a wake-up call"?
He's-he's saying that actually we've got
people in the city who live on welfare...
Would I... would I have seen
any of... any of your windows?
A couple of weeks ago
I did a... I did a thing with... hostages.
- The people in blindfolds.
- Yeah.
I thought it was like late '80s.
That's in-interesting.
Let's just say I'm really not
a big fan of Jimmy Breslin.
Well, he's the reason I became
a writer, but that's not important.
Harry, you and Marie
are both from New Jersey.
- Really?
- Where are you from?
- South Orange.
- Haddonfield.
- So, what are we gonna order?
- I'm gonna start with the grilled radicchio.
Jess, Sally is a great orderer.
Not only does she always pick
the best thing on the menu,
but she orders it in a way that even
the chef didn't know how good it could be.
I think restaurants
have become too important.
I agree.
"Restaurants are to people in the '80s
what theatre was to people in the '60s."
- I read that in a magazine.
- I wrote that.
- Get outta here.
- No, I did. I wrote that.
I've never quoted anything from
a magazine in my life. That's amazing.
Don't you think it's amazing?
And you wrote it?
I also wrote
"Pesto is quiche of the '80s."
- Get over yourself.
- I did.
- Where did I read that?
- "New York Magazine".
Sally writes
for "New York Magazine".
You know, that piece had a real impact
on me. I-I don't know much about writing...
It spoke to you,
and that pleases me.
I-I mean, I really....
you have to admire
people who-who can be
as... that articulate.
Nobody has ever quoted
me back to me before.
Oh! I've been looking for
a red suede pump.
What do you think of Jess?
Well, uh...
Do you think
you could go out with him?
- I don't know...
- Cause I feel really comfortable with him.
- You wanna go out with Jess.
- If it would be all right with you.
Sure. Sure.
I'm just worried about Harry.
He's very sensitive,
he's going through a rough period,
and I... I just don't want you
to reject him right now.
- I wouldn't. I totally understand.
- Okay.
If you don't think you're gonna
call Marie, do you mind if I call her?
- No, no.
- Good. Good. Good.
But for tonight
you shouldn't.
I mean, Sally's
very vulnerable right now.
I mean,
you can call Marie, it's fine,
but let's just wait a week or so,
you know?
Don't make any moves tonight.
Fine. No problem.
I wasn't even thinking about tonight.
Well, I don't really feel much
like walking any more.
I think I'll get a cab.
- I'll go with you.
- Great. Taxi!
A man came to me and said
"I found nice girl for you."
"She lives in the next village
and she is ready for marriage."
We were not supposed to meet
until the wedding,
but I wanted to make sure.
So I sneak into her village,
hid behind a tree,
watch her washing the clothes.
I think if I don't like the way
she looks, I don't marry her.
So I said "Okay" to the man.
We get married.
We married for 55 years.
- I have to get this. I have to get this.
- Harry, we're here for Jess and Marie.
I know. We'll find them something.
It's great stuff here.
Should have gone
to the plant store.
- Here. Perfect for them.
- What's that?
Battery-operated
pith helmet, with fan.
- Why is this necessary in life?
- I don't know.
Look. Look at this.
Also makes great fries.
Oh... Oh-ho. Good.
Call off the dogs. The hunt is over.
Sally, this is the greatest.
Sally, please report to me.
Look at this. This is the greatest.
You're gonna love this.
This is a singing machine.
Look, you sing the-the-the lead
and this has the backup
and everything.
This is from "Oklahoma".
Here's the lyrics right here.
- "Surrey with the Fringe on Top."
- Yes, perfect.
What?
It's my voice, isn't it?
You hate my voice.
- I know, it's terrible. Joe hated my voice...
- It's Helen.
Helen?
She's coming
right towards me.
- How are you, Harry?
- Fine. I'm fine.
This is Ira Stone.
Harry Burns.
Harry.
I'm sorry. This is Sally Albright.
Helen Hillson... and Ira.
Sally.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
Well...
- See you.
- Yeah. Bye.
Nice to meet you... Ira.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm perfect.
She looked weird,
didn't she?
She looked really weird.
She looked very weird
I've never seen her before.
Trust me. She looked weird.
Her legs looked heavy.
- Really. She must be retaining water.
- Harry...
Believe me,
the woman saved everything.
Sure you're okay?
Oh, I'm fine. Look,
it had to happen at some point.
In a city of eight million people,
you're bound to run into your ex-wife.
So, boom, it happened.
And now I'm fine.
I like it. It works.
It says "home" to me.
All right. All right.
We'll let Harry and Sally be the judge.
What do you think?
- It's nice.
- Case closed.
Of course he likes it,
he's a guy. Sally?
What's so awful about it?
It's so awful, there's no way to even begin
to explain what's so awful about it.
Honey, I don't object
to any of your things.
If we had an extra room,
you could put all your things in it,
including your bar stools...
Honey, wait, wait, wait.
Honey, honey, wait, wait, wait.
You don't like my bar stools?
Harry, come on,
someone has to be on my side.
I'm on your side. I'm just trying
to help you have good taste.
I have good taste.
Everybody thinks they have
good taste and a sense of humor,
but they couldn't possibly
all have good taste.
You know, it's funny.
We started out like this, Helen and I.
We had bank walls, we hung things,
we picked out tiles together.
Then you know what happens?
Six years later
you find yourself singing
"Surrey with the Fringe on Top"
in front of Ira!
Do we have to talk
about this right now?
Yes. I think that right now actually is
the perfect time to talk about this,
because I want our friends to benefit
from the wisdom of my experience.
Right now
everything is great.
Everyone is happy, everone is in love,
and that's wonderful.
But you gotta know
that sooner or later,
you're gonna be screaming at each other
about who's gonna get this dish.
This 8-dollar dish will cost you
1,000 dollar in phone calls
to the legal firm of
"That's mine, this is yours".
- Harry...
- Please.
Jess, Marie,
do me a favour for your own good.
Put your name
in your books right now
before they get mixed up and
you don't know whose is whose,
because some day,
believe it or not,
you'll go 15 rounds over
who's gonna get this coffee table.
This stupid, wagon-wheel,
Roy-Rogers, garage-sale coffee table!
- I thought you liked it.
- I was being nice!
He just bumped into Helen.
I want you to know...
that I will never want
that wagon-wheel coffee table.
I know, I know,
I shouldn't have done it.
Harry, you're gonna have
to try and find a way
of not expressing
every feeling that you have,
every moment
that you have them.
- Oh, really?
- Yes.
There are times
and places for things.
Well, the next time you're giving
a lecture series on social graces,
would you let know,
cause I'll sign up.
Hey! You don't have
to take your anger out on me.
Oh, I think I'm entitled
to throw a little anger your way.
Especially when I'm being told how
to live my life by Miss Hospital Corners.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I mean, nothing bothers you!
- You never get upset about anything!
- Don't be ridiculous.
What?
You never get upset about Joe.
I never see that back up on you.
How is that possible?
Don't you experience
any feelings of loss?
I don't have to take
this crap from you.
If you're so over Joe,
why aren't you seeing anyone?
I see people!
See people... Have you slept with
one person since you broke up with Joe?
What the hell does that
have to do with anything?
That will prove I'm over Joe
because I fuck somebody?
Harry, you're gonna have
to move back to New Jersey
because you've slept
with everybody in New York
and I don't see that turning Helen
into a faint memory for you.
Besides, I will make love
to somebody when it is making love.
Not the way you do it,
like you're out for revenge or something.
- Are you finished now?
- Yes.
- Can I say something?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Don't say a word.
It's a monkey, it's a monkey.
Monkey see, monkey do.
- It's... it's an ape. Going ape.
- It's a baby!
Planet of the Apes!
Planet of the Apes?
She just said it's a baby!
How 'bout
Planet of the Dopes?
It doesn't look like a baby.
Bet up. Big mouth.
Mick Jagger is a baby!
- Baby ape! Baby ape!
- Stop with the apes, will you?
- Uh, baby's breath.
- Baby... Rosemary's Baby's mouth?
- "Won't You Come Home, Bill Baby?"
- Baby, baby... Kiss the baby!
"Melancholy Baby's Mouth"!
Baby fish... Baby-fish mouth!
Baby-fish mouth!
- 15 seconds.
- A big baby mouth.
- B-b-baby Boom!
- Baby...
Draw something
resembling anything!
- Crying baby. Kiss the baby.
- Baby spitting up... Exorcist Baby!
- Baby... "Yes, sir, that's my baby".
- "No, sir, don't mean maybe."
- That's it. Time's up.
- Baby talk.
Baby talk? Wh-wh-what's that?
That's not a saying.
Oh, but "baby-fish mouth" is sweeping
the nation. I hear them talking.
Final score. Our team: 110.
You guys: 60.
- Ouch. Fix. Definitely a fix.
- Pathetic.
- I can't draw.
- No, that's a baby, and it's clearly talking.
You're wonderful.
- All right, who wants coffee?
- I do, and I love you.
- D'you have any tea?
- Industrial strength.
- I'll help you. Decaf?
- Yeah.
- Three.
- Yes, please.
- Where's the bathroom?
- Through that door, down the hall.
Never looked
like a baby to me.
- Which part?
- All of it.
Hey, Jess, you were gonna show me
the cover of your new book.
Oh, yeah, yeah,
it's-it's in the den.
Look, uh, Julian,
help yourself.
Have some, uh, more wine,
whatever you like, okay?
I like saying "it's in the den".
It's got a nice ring to it.
Emily's a little young for Harry,
don't you think?
Well, she's young,
but look what she's done.
What has she done?
She makes desserts.
Does Julian seem
a little stuffy to you?
He's a good guy.
You should talk to 'im. Get to know 'im.
He's too tall to talk to.
She makes 3,500
chocolate-mousse pies a week.
Emily is "Aunt Emily"?
He took us all to a Met game
last week. It was great.
You all went
to a Met game together?
Yeah, but... but, yeah,
it was a last-minute thing.
But Sally hates baseball.
Harry doesn't even like sweets.
- Julian is great.
- I know. He's a grown-up.
Emily is terrific.
Yeah. Of course,
when I asked her where she was
when Kennedy was shot,
she said "Ted Kennedy was shot?"
No...
- Hello?
- Are you alone?
Yeah.
I was just finishing a book.
- Could you come over?
- What's the matter?
- He's getting married.
- Who?
Joe!
I'll be right there.
- Hi.
- You all right?
Come on in.
- I'm sorry to call you so late.
- It's all right.
- I need a Kleenex.
- Okay.
Okay. Okay.
He just called me up.
"Wanted to see how you were."
"Fine. How are you?"
"Fine."
His secretary's on vacation,
everything's all backed up.
He's got a big case in Newark...
blah, blah, blah.
And I'm sitting on the phone thinking
"I am over him, I really am over him,
I can't believe I was ever
remotely interested in any of this."
And then he said
"I have some news."
She works in his office. She's a paralegal.
Her name is Kimberly.
He just met her!
She's supposed to be
his transitional person,
she's not supposed
to be "the one"!
All this time, I've been saying...
that he didn't wanna get married.
But the truth is...
he didn't wanna marry me.
He didn't love me.
If you could take him back
right now, would you?
No!
But why didn't he
wanna marry me?
- What's the matter with me?
- Nothing.
- I'm difficult.
- You're challenging.
I'm too structured.
I'm completely closed off.
- But in a good way.
- No, no, no. I drove him away.
- And I'm gonna be 40!
- When?
- Some day.
- In eight years.
But it's there! It's just sitting there
like this big dead end.
And it's not the same for men.
Charlie Chaplin had babies
when he was 73.
Yeah, but he was too old
to pick 'em up.
Ohh, come here.
Come here.
It's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be fine, you'll see.
Go ahead. It's not one
of my favourites anyway.
It's gonna be okay. Hm?
Hm? Okay? Okay.
I'll make some tea.
Harry, could you just
hold me a little longer?
Oh, sure.
Okay? Hm?
- Are you comfortable?
- Sure.
D'you want something
to drink or something?
No, I'm okay.
I'm gonna get up for some water,
so it's really no trouble.
Okay. Water.
You have all your video tapes
alphabetized and on index cards.
Thank you.
- D'you wanna watch something?
- No. Not unless you do.
No. That's okay.
- D'you wanna go to sleep?
- Okay.
- Where are you going?
- I gotta go.
Gotta go home,
I gotta change my clothes
and then I have to go to work.
And so do you.
But after work, I'd like to take you out
to dinner, if you're free. Are you free?
- Yes.
- Fine. I'll call you later.
- Fine.
- Yours.
- Hello.
- I'm sorry to call so early.
- Are you all right?
No one I know
would call at this hour.
- I did something terrible.
- What did you do?
- No one I know would call at this hour.
- It's so awful.
- I need to talk.
- What happened?
What's the matter?
- Harry came over last night.
- I went over to Sally's last night.
Because I was upset that
Joe was getting married.
And one thing led to another.
And before I knew,
we were kissing. And then...
To make a long story short...
- We did it.
They did it!
- That's great, Sally!
- We've been praying for it.
You should've done it
in the first place.
For months we've been saying
you should do it.
- You guys belong together.
- It's like killing two birds with one stone.
It's like two wrongs
make a right.
- How was it?
- The durring part was good...
- ... but then I felt suffocated.
- ... then I guess it wasn't.
- Jesus, I'm sorry.
- The worst.
- I had to get outta there.
- He just disappeared.
- I feel so bad.
- I'm so embarrassed.
I don't blame you.
- That's horrible.
- I think I'm coming down with something.
I think I'm catching a cold.
Look, it would have been great
if it worked out, but it didn't.
I should never
go to bed with anyone
when you found out
your ex-boyfriend is getting married.
- Who's that talking?
- Who?
Is that Jess on the phone?
- It's Jane Fonda on the VCR.
- It's Bryan Gumble.
D'you wanna
come over for breakfast?
- No, I'm not up to it.
- No, I feel too awful.
- Good.
- I-I mean, it's so early.
- But call me later if you want.
- I'll call you later, okay?
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye.
- God!
- I know.
Tell me I'll never have
to be out there again.
You will never have
I'll just say
we made a mistake.
Sally... it was a mistake.
I just hope
I get to say it first.
I hope she says it
before I do.
- It was a mistake.
- I am so relieved that you think so, too.
I'm not saying
last night wasn't great.
- It was.
- Yes, it was.
- We just never should have done it.
- I couldn't agree more.
- I'm so relieved.
- Great.
Yeah.
Two mixed green salads.
It is so nice when you can sit
with someone and not have to talk. Hmm?
It's just like, most of the time,
you go to bed with someone,
then she tells you all her stories,
you tell her your stories...
But with Sally and me,
we'd already heard each other's stories.
So once we went to bed, we didn't know
what we were supposed to do.
- You know?
- Sure, Harry.
I don't know.
Maybe you get to a certain point
in a relationship
where it's just too late
to have sex. You know?
Is Harry bringing anyone
to the wedding?
I don't think so.
- Is he seeing anyone?
- He was seeing this anthropologist, but...
- What does she look like?
- Thin, pretty, big tits.
Your basic nightmare.
What d'you think?
Oh, Marie...
- Tell the truth.
- It's just beautiful.
We are gathered here today to celebrate
the marriage of Marie... and Jess.
And to consecrate
their vows of matrimony.
The vows they will take
join their lives.
The wine they will share
binds all their hopes together.
And by the rings
they will wear,
they will be known to all
as husband and wife.
I've never seen her so happy.
She's a totally different person.
Oh, yeah, she is. It's great,
but what're we gonna do about you?
- Me?
- Hon!
- Yeah.
- Wanna dance?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, I do.
- Excuse us.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Nice ceremony.
- Beautiful.
Boy, the holidays are rough.
Every year I just try to get
from the day before Thanksgiving
to the day after New Year's.
A lot of suicides.
- Would you like a pea pod with shrimp?
- Thank you.
- How've you been?
- Fine.
- Are you seeing anybody?
- Harry.
- What?
- I don't wanna talk about this.
- Why not?
- I don't want to talk about it.
Why can't we get past this?
I mean, are we gonna
carry this thing around forever?
- Forever? It just happened!
- It happened three weeks ago.
You know how a year to a person
is like seven years to a dog?
Yes.
Is one of us supposed
to be a dog in this scenario?
- Yes.
- Who is the dog?
- You are.
- I am. I am the dog!
- Mmm-hmm.
- I am the dog! I...
I don't see that, Harry.
If anybody is the dog, you are the dog.
You wanna act like what happened
didn't mean anything.
I'm not saying
it didn't mean anything,
I'm saying why does it
have to mean everything?
Because it does!
And you should know that
better than anybody,
because the minute that it happens
you walk right out the door!
- I didn't walk out.
- No, sprinted is more like it.
- We both agreed it was a mistake.
- The worst mistake I ever made!
- What do you want from me?
- I don't want anything from you.
Fine. Fine. But let's
just get one thing straight.
I did not go over there that night
to make love to you.
That is not why I went there.
But you looked up at me
with these big weepy eyes.
"Don't go home tonight, Harry.
Hold me a little longer, Harry."
What was I supposed to do?
What are you saying?
You took pity on me?
- No. I was...
- Fuck you!
Everybody, could I... have
your attention, please?
I'd like to propose a toast.
To Harry and Sally.
If Marie or I had found
either of them remotely attractive,
we would not be here today.
Hi, it's me.
It's the holiday season,
and I thought I'd remind you
that this is the season
of charity and forgiveness.
And, although it's not widely known,
it is also the season of grovelling.
So, if you felt
like calling me back,
I'd be more than happy to do
the traditional Christmas grovelling.
Give me a call.
Hi, I'm not home right now.
I'll call you right back.
If you're there, please pick up
the phone. I really wanna talk to you.
The fact that you're not answering
leads me to believe
you're either, A: not at home,
B: home, but don't wanna talk to me,
or C: home, desperately
wanna talk to me,
but trapped
under something heavy.
If it's either A or C,
please call me back.
Obviously she doesn't
wanna talk to me.
What do I have to do,
be hit over the head?
If she wants to call me,
she'll call me.
I'm through making
a schmuck out of myself.
If you're feeling
sad and lonely
There's a service
I can render
Tell the one
who digs you only
I can be
so warm and tender
Call me.
Maybe it's late
to just call me
Don't be afraid
to just phone moi
Call me
and I'll be around
Give me a call.
- Hi, Harry.
- Hello. Hi! Hi!
I di... I didn't know that you would...
That you were there.
- What're you doing?
- I was just on my way out.
Where you going?
- What d'you want, Harry?
- Nothing. Nothing.
I... I... just called
to say I'm sorry.
Okay.
- I gotta go.
- Wait a second. Wait... wait a second.
What're you doin' for New Year's?
Are you going to the Tylers' party?
Cause I don't have a date.
And if you don't have a date,
we always said that if
neither one of us had a date,
we could be together
for New Year's and kick in, you know...
I can't do this any more.
I am not your consolation prize.
Goodbye.
And here we are
once again.
The 16th annual "New Year's
Rockin' Eve", coming to you live...
What's so bad about this?
You got Dick Clark. That's tradition.
You got Mallomars,
the greatest cookie of all time.
And you're about to give the Knicks
their first championship since 1973.
I don't know why I let you
drag me to this.
This is much better. Fresh air,
I've the streets all to myself.
Who needs to be
at a big, crowded party,
pretending
to have a good time?
Plus, this is the perfect time
to catch up on my window-shopping.
This is good.
So the guy says...
"Read the card."
- I'm going home.
- You'll never get a taxi.
Oh, God!
You realize, of course, that
we could never be friends.
- Why not?
- What I'm saying
is that men and women
can't be friends,
because the sex part
always gets in the way.
That's not true!
No man can be friends
with a woman he finds attractive.
He always wants
to have sex with her.
What if they don't wanna
have sex with you?
Doesn't matter. Because
the sex thing is already out there,
so the friendship
is ultimately doomed.
And that is
the end of the story.
Well, I guess
we're not gonna be friends then.
- Guess not.
- That's too bad.
You were the only person
that I knew in New York.
- I'm going.
- It's almost midnight.
The thought of
not kissing somebody is just...
I'll kiss you.
Hey, taxi! Taxi!
Taxi!
Shit.
- Come on, stay. Please.
- Thanks, Jess. I just... I have to go.
- Oh, wait two minutes.
- I'll call you tomorrow.
I've been doin' a lot of thinkin',
and the thing is... I love you.
- What?
- I love you.
How d'you expect me
to respond to this?
How 'bout
you love me, too?
How 'bout I'm leaving?
Doesn't what I said
mean anything to you?
I'm sorry, Harry.
I know it's New Year's Eve,
I know you're feeling lonely,
but you just can't show up here,
tell me you love me
and expect that
to make everything all right.
- It doesn't work this way.
- Well, how does it work?
- I don't know, but not this way.
- How 'bout this way?
I love that you get cold
when it's 71 degrees out.
I love that it takes you an hour
and a half to order a sandwich.
I love that you get
a little crinkle above your nose
when you're looking at me
like I'm nuts.
I love that after
I spend a day with you,
I can still smell
your perfume on my clothes.
And I love that
you are the last person
I wanna talk to
before I go to sleep at night.
And it's not because I'm lonely,
and it's not because it's New Year's Eve.
I came here tonight because,
when you realize
you wanna spend
the rest of your life with somebody,
you want the rest of your life
to start as soon as possible.
You see?
That is just like you, Harry.
You say things like that and you make it
impossible for me to hate you!
And I hate you, Harry.
I really hate you.
I hate you.
What does this song mean? My whole life,
I don't know what this song means.
I mean "Should auld acquaintance
be forgot",
does that mean that we
should forget old acquaintance?
Or does it mean that
we haven't to forget them,
we should remember them?
Which is not possible
because we already forgot 'em.
Well, maybe it just means
that... we should remember
that we forgot them,
or something.
Anyway,
it's about old friends.
The first time we met
we hated each other.
No, you didn't hate me.
I hated you.
The second time we met,
you didn't even remember me.
I did, too!
I remembered you.
The third time we met,
we became friends.
- We were friends for a long time.
- And then we weren't.
And then we fell in love.
- Three months later we got married.
- It only took three months.
Twelve years
and three months.
We had this really really
wonderful wedding.
It was... it really was a...
- ... a beautiful wedding.
- It was great.
We had
this enormous... coconut cake.
Huge coconut cake
with the... with the tiers
and there was this-thid very rich
chocolate sauce on the side...
Right. Cause not everybody likes it
on the cake cause it makes it very soggy.
Particularly,
the coconut soaks up a lot,
so you really... it's important
to keep it on the side.
Right.